EVERETT CLINT ESPINOZA

WEB DEVELOPER | SYSTEMS ENGINEER AUSTIN, TX

PHONE 512-633-4919
EMAIL CESPIN@GMAIL.COM

WEBSITE CLINTESPINOZA.COM

LINKEDIN

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/CLINTESPINOZA

GITHUB GITHUB.COM/CLINTE

SUMMARY

I'm a web developer trained through General Assembly's WDI Program in Full Stack Web Development. My goal is to create informative and useful web applications that are intuitive and beautiful. Leveraging my past experience as a systems engineer, I create things that solve problems.

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY - AUSTIN, TX

APRIL 2015 - JULY 2015

Completed the 13 week web development immersive program focusing on a broad range of technologies including JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Node, Backbone, SQL and noSQL.

Worked individually and in teams to create useful and Agile-driven web apps including:

TacoFinder – Find the best tacos in the Austin area.

FlightTracker – Track what aiplanes are above you in real time.

AirportDelays – Find out if there is a delay at a user selected airport in the United States, the cause of the delay and the estimated duration.

IT CONSULTANT - AUSTIN, TX / SANTA FE, NM

2008 - 2015

Independent consultant working with individual clients and in contractor partnership for IT projects including:

Tipit Communications - Recommended and executed improvements of server/storage systems in a Dell-centric data center that hosted online news stations for Time Warner, increasing productivity and lowering down time.

Bravo Tech - Systems Engineer reporting directly to client CIO of TMST Inc. maintaining data center (EMC Clariion SANs, Celerra NAS, Dell PowerEdge Servers) and assisting with their IT outsourcing project as server/storage advisor.

DELL INC. - ROUND ROCK, TX

1998 - 2008

Point of contact for system performance analytic support for international sales and marketing groups leveraging the collective expertise and resources of the entire Performance Team.

Systems Engineer developing products based on performance in the client, workstation and server lines of business.

EDUCATION

TRINITY UNIVERSITY - SAN ANTONIO, TX

Bachelor of Arts in International Studies and Spanish

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby

Frameworks and Libraries

jQuery, AJAX, Rails, Active Record, Backbone, Node, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools

Git/Github, Sublime, Agile Development processes, NPM, Bower

OTHER SKILLS

Storage

SAN, NAS, RAID

Dell Servers and Clients

Dell 8th through 10th Generation clients and servers.

Managerial

- Led a team of aviation fuelers at Seattle Tacoma International airport to ensure timely and customer focused service.
- Team lead for various development teams at Dell Inc.
- Mentor for new hires in the Client Performance team.